# SKILLS

#### **Professional**

- Data Analytics (Predictive Analysis, Data Capture, Text Analysis, Web Scraping etc.)
- Statistical Modelling
- Data Visualization
- Business Analysis

#### **Technical**

- R, Python, SQL
- Tableau, Alteryx,
- Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics
- SAP Hybris, Adobe Experience Manager, Adobe Target, JIRA, Confluence
- Robotic Process Automation
- Natural Language Processing (Classification and Categorization, Intent and Salience)

## **EDUCATION**

- Certificate in Business Analysis (Harvard Online, 2020)
- PGP Predictive Business Analytics (Northwestern University 2019)
- Scholarship Student MSc Innovation Management (University of Strathclyde 2019)
- MSc Business and Management (University of Strathclyde 2015)

#### **PROFILE**

Data scientist with 7+ years experience in collecting, analysing and interpreting large data sets, to drive successful business solutions.

Proficient in Predictive Models using Predictive Analysis, Statistical Modelling, Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Computer Vision (CV) with Strong problem solving and analytical solution building skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Head of Data Analytics Unyscape, Noida, India

02/2020 - Present

- Client: Premier BioPharmaceuticals Company
  - Leading off-shore delivery of Demand Forecast, Lead Time Suggestions and Field Force Optimization (using Predictive Modelling, RNN and Smoothening)
- Client: Leading Health Information Technology Company
- Applied Data Mining and automated Data Pipelines to Streamline multiple Data Sources; while ensuring data quality validations and raising alerts for anomalies (Using R and Python)
- Supported Executive decision making with automated Data Reporting and Visualization, with a continued view of data integrity across transformations (Using R and SQL)
- Client: Market Leader in Retail Behaviour Analytics
  - Executed Large-Scale Data Gathering, Processing and Readiness Automation (using Alteryx)
  - Created SKU Recommendation and Demand Forecasting with visualization Tableau.

## Data Scientist Tata Advanced Systems, Noida, India

12/2018-02/2020

- Worked on a Homomorphic Encryption System to encrypt data while ensuring security between two devices, withstanding limitations of realtime processing and latency on smaller devices. (Using R, SQL, BigQuery, Robotic Process Automation)
- Used predictive analysis (time-series based prediction modelling and mean-baseline based prediction methodology) within supply chain logistics to minimize storage oxidisation and raw material wastage.
- Developed data-gathering and reporting structures Via Automated PPTs and Data Studio.

# Data Analyst Info Nova, Noida, India

05/2017-11/2018

- Created a Candidate Screening system using NLP to identify and rate candidates per identified requirements. (Using R, Google Cloud, Google Big Query, Hadoop and several NLP based processes)
- Implemented classification system to ascertain intent in an online forum.
  Analysed text using regression-based machine learning, Sentiment
  Analysis, Feature Extraction and Topic modelling using Latent Dirichlet
  Allocation
- Created a system to identify Higher Recovery feasibility for accounts within a Loans Management System. Using machine learning-based method to predict the possible outcomes.

#### **Previous Experience**

- ZichBuy Pvt Ltd Co-Founder
- Urja Packaging Manager, Packaging and Production
- Ansh Studios Art Coordinator